Guide to the Eleanor Robson Belmont (Mrs. August Belmont) Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Eleanor Robson Belmont collection
1913-1949
MS 668
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Chiefly autographs and letters collected by Eleanor R. Belmont in connection with a copy of the Treaty of Versailles for which she wanted original signatures. There is also some personal correspondence connected with gathering the letters and a small amount of memorabilia.
Belmont, Eleanor Robson, 1879-1979
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Colonel E.M. House Papers (MS 466).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of autographs and letters collected by Eleanor Robson Belmont in connection with a copy of the Treaty of Versailles for which she wanted original signatures. The correspondence in the collection includes cover letters from people who helped her secure the signatures as well as letters from some of the signatories of the Treaty. There is also a small amount of memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
Eleanor Robson Belmont was born in Lancashire, England in 1879. In 1897, she graduated from St. Peter's Academy, in Staten Island, New York. Upon graduation, Belmont became an actress in California and New York. After her marriage to August Belmont on February 26, 1910, she quit the acting business and focused her attention on philanthropy. Belmont died in 1979.
Treaty of Versailles (1919 June 28); United States -- Foreign relations; Autographs
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - Astor, Nancy (Langhorne), undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Baker, Newton D., 1934 March 14, 1937 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Balfour, Arthur James, undated
      General
      See also: Houghton, Alanson B.
    - Barnes, Sir George S., 1936 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bliss, Tasker H., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chamberlain, Sir Austen, 1936 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Davis, John W., 1929 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Eaton, Charles A., 1918 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Gesson[ ], 1930 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Gibson, Mrs. Charles Dana, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Grey, Edward Grey, 1917 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Haig of Bemersyde, Douglas Haig, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Harbord, Eunice O., 1931 April 9, 17 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Harbord, James G., 1936 April 24, May 11, 1942 January 8, 1944 May 26, October 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1920 December 18, 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Houghton, Alanson B., 1931 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - House, Edward M., 1917 July 12, 1918 June 15, 1931 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Houston, David Franklin, 1930 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hymans, Paul, 1930 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Jusserand, Jean Adrien Antoine Jules, 1917 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - La[ ], M. de, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Landowne, Lord, 1913 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Law, Andrew Bonar, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lindsay, Ronald, 1934 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1918 December 24, 1919 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Massey, William F., 1920 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Me[ ], 1936 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Orlando, Vittorio E., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - [Parish?], George, 1932 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Pershing, John J., 1936 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Salter, Sir James Arthur, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sifton, Arthur L., 1919 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sifton, Lewis R., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Singh, Ganga, Maharaja of Bikaner, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Stanley, Sir Arthur, 1921 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Thomas, Godfrey, 1936 July 18, 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Veniselos, Eleutherios K., 1923 January 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Veniselos, Helena, 1949 March 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - White, Henry, 1920 February 20, 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia, 1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)